<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:33:40 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:33:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Struggling with Identity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that is extremely important when you are trying to put yourself and your talents out into the world, is to know and be confident in who you are. This is easier said than done and many of us well know. But if you don’t know who you are how can you effectively communicate what is special or valuable about yourself to others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I was writing up a new resume, and on the advice of several career counselors I am adding a personality statement. I used to have a mission statement, but if you are applying to a position, your mission is clear (get a job). Instead, what I want to add is a statement that show the recruiter or employer a quick and clear insight into who I am, what I can bring to their organization, and an indication of how I will fit with my potential coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tall order. In just one or two sentences I need to tell the person reading my resume that I am friendly, and courteous. That I give my advice when I have insight, and that I always ask for help when I need it. I need them to know that I can learn on the job, and that I will invest the same amount of effort in them that they will in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in the past you could count on your cover letter to do this for you, but with resume getting aggregated and concentrated with modern job portals. Employers now have hundreds (not dozens) of resumes to get through and most, not all, but most cover letters end up collecting virtual dust. So, the point is to make the most of those first few lines, because that is all you will likely get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what do I want to be to them in those few words? I am confident, without saying that I am. I am talented, but driven to learn. I am friendly, and kind, and generous with my efforts. I want them to know that I am a relentless optimist and always approach new challenges with a positive attitude. I may be old for someone just starting in this industry, but that only makes me more driven to catch up to my peers. It also mean that I bring a different perspective to my work and in turn their team. And finally I want to leave them with the impression that I will not only meet their requirements, but that I will exceed their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that is quite a lot… but lets work through this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My drive to learn has taken me down many avenues, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;del&gt;everything that I have been challenged with&lt;/del&gt;&lt;em&gt;every challenge that I&lt;del&gt;‘ve&lt;/del&gt; face&lt;del&gt;d~~_ I always bring a positive attitude, a kind spirit, and an open mind. Having only recently found my true calling, I am eager to make up for lost time, and to find a ~~place where I can call home.&lt;/del&gt; _community of peers to grow with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so here is the new version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My drive to learn has taken me down many avenues, and in every challenge that I face I always bring a positive attitude, a kind spirit, and an open mind. Having only recently found my true calling, I am eager to make up for lost time, and to find a community of peers to grow with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, I honestly didn’t think I would get it that quick, I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; hoping that talking my way through the purpose of the statement would clarify message, but it was surprisingly effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, if there is a message you take from this entry, it’s this: Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is you are trying to wrap your head around, and in what ever form is comfortable. Write it down. Even if it only bullet points on a napkin, write it down. And keep writing until the subject is clear to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 18:45:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/career/2016/07/08/struggling-with-identity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/career/2016/07/08/struggling-with-identity/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Measure Twice, Cut Once and Start Over</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The saying “measure twice, cut once” is wise advice about the benefits of planning when starting a project. It is absolutely true that a little planing now will save you a lot of work later. But what often goes unsaid is that it is precisely in the moments when you make mistakes that you learn the deepest and most lost lasting lessons. Indeed, it is only through these mistakes that the masters that dispense this wisdom became so wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to struggle through a project filled with mistakes to gain the most out of it. This is so true that it might be better to say “Measure Twice, Cut Once and then Start Over”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Savage says that he always buys enough material to build a new project twice. He has been making professionally for years and yet he knows to allow for mistakes. He anticipates and even celebrates them, because he knows that it is in our failures where true personal growth happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that something I need to be more open to is the possibility of starting from square one on a project, giving the whole project the benefit of what I have already learned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 11:24:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/learning/2016/07/06/measure-twice-cut-once/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/learning/2016/07/06/measure-twice-cut-once/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Knowing the right thing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to know that you are on the right path. Will learning all this CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, C++, etc. help me find a job I love? I hope so, but if I am honest with myself, there is a part of me that really doubts it. That part of me is convinced that I need to go back to working part time at the library and resign myself to poverty, and wait for the National Basic Income to come into being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I choose to ignore that voice, that guys is a lazy jerk, and he wants me to be one too. I have chosen this path carefully, I did my research, and I consulted with experts, friends and family. I don’t trust in my intuition, I trust in my decision. I have set a course and now I will follow it. I know I have the ability, and I think I have the talent, all I need to provide now is the commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their are a lot of ways to sabotage yourself, but none are easier then second guessing a decision to learn. There are many paths in life that need to be questioned and requestioned, but learning a new skill set will always benefit you in the end no matter the outcome. Being scared is natural but there is only one way to master your life, make the decision to learn. And don’t stop learning. Read and watch, and listen, and discover, everything you can about your thing. Make it apart of your identity, make it so that you wouldn’t know what to do if you couldn’t do this thing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this won’t make you happy, I need to be clear on this. If you have food, shelter, your health, and loved ones, and you are still unhappy, you need to talk about it, if not with professional, than with someone. Money, and success will not change your perception of the world, it will amplify it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you have a positive outlook on life, skill will make you valuable, and hard-work will make you productive. Even if you don’t end up wealth beyond reason, how could you not take pride in that. If you can produce work of value than you will be appreciated, by someone if not everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t know that you are doing the &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; thing, but I think you can know that you can know that you are doing a &lt;strong&gt;worthwhile&lt;/strong&gt; thing. And maybe thats all you need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 09:23:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/career/2016/07/05/traveling-the-path/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/career/2016/07/05/traveling-the-path/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll: First Impressions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned a few days ago in my post about [what I’ve already learned][https://medium.com/@kravenoff42/what-ive-already-learned-da6df98cf48#.dyu33ienm] about software so far. I am currently deigning my own personal site. This is where I intend to keep completed project, along with some works in progress, my new blog, and a short description of myself. I’d also like the site to be sort of a playground for tools and methods that I am learning.
I mentioned that I think that [Jekyll][https://jekyllrb.com] was the likely candidate for building the site, I’d like to unpack that a little today.
—
##What is Jekyll?
Jekyll is a tool for build static sites. What this means is that you won’t be use any bots to serve up a page upon each request. Normally this is considered a useful model because it ensures that you content is always up-to-date. So, if you have a site that is displaying a large data set that is always in flux, you might would to use this more standard method.
With a static site the pages you view are fixed, every user that views your site with see the same structure, regardless of user group. This can be a problem, but in many cases it wouldn’t ever come up. This is especially true to sites that primarily serve as an archive of information, like a portfolio.
Now, I’d like to clarify that the term static here, does not refer to the page display, or external data. you can still use APIs to inject dynamic content, and you can still use JavaScript to add behavior to the pages. it just means that the file structure does not change between builds.
To solve the problem of keeping your info updated without a database, Jekyll rebuilds the site each time a piece of content is saved, or a new file is created. This means that the Jekyll team has also made if very easy to adjust your content from the back end.
All of your layout info is stored in one folder, your styling in in another, and the content is also separate, this makes is easy to identify where you changes need to be made and makes sure the mistakes don’t necessarily lead to a cascading failure. In fact, if you are smart about how you separate your code you can make sure that the content, layout, styling and behavior can all fail independently with out crashing the whole site. This is called Graceful Degradation, and it a concept I am sure I will get into another time.
Once you have the code how you want, you run Jekyll from your command line and it builds the HTML, with all the appropriate files and folders. Presto! New Site!
—
##Why Jekyll?
So, why is all of this good for me? Well, the static site format is one that I am most familiar with, this is the way site were built in the 90’s and early 2000’s so I know how to think about the structure. Jekyll also come with language that understands blogs, one of the primary features I am interested in. And probably the best reason, for using it is that is allows me to host my site on GitHub free of charge. All that I need to pay for is my Domain name, and point it to the write spot. Using a static site is also more secure since there is now database to hack.
That is what I have learned some far, I have only been messing with Jekyll for a few days now, so I with have to make another post in the future with other insights.
Do you have any points that I missed? Did I misrepresent any of the features of Jekyll? Let me know, and I will make the corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/tech/jekyll/2016/07/04/jekyll-first-impressions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tech/jekyll/2016/07/04/jekyll-first-impressions/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting More out of My Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, was the First time in a long time that I felt like I really go the most out of my day. I cleaned three fairly small, but important areas of my house, I started work on my new personal website, I helped my wife get her work done by watching our daughter, wrote an article for medium –and– spend the evening with my wife and friends, just having fun… guilt free fun. And for the first time ever, I think, it was on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity has always been some that I have struggled with. For a long time I told myself that I was just better at working under pressure. And then after college, I owned up to the fact that I was just a procrastinator. But like most of us that did not stop the procrastination. What it took, for me, was a blow up argument with my wife about how I didn’t keep the house like she wanted me to. And a new app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was insistent that I could not clean the house like she wanted, “I’m not you, I need you help”. This sounded very reasonable to both of us. And she reluctantly agreed to start a running list of tasks that I would do everyday, for two weeks. “If is really not working after that, we’ll figure something else out”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 4 days, things started to fall apart. She would forget to add to the list and I wouldn’t remind her. She would be preoccupied and unable to think of something, it did take 2 weeks to see it was not going to work. Luckily, the things my wife had brought up in the argument had stuck with me, I was unfocused, lazy, easily distracted, and a clean house was not motivation enough to drive me. This was how I lived, but I had to admit, it was not working. So, I began a hunt for an app that I could program to run my life. Something I could set the parameters for and only think about when I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I downloaded maybe a dozen to-do apps and habit apps, and started quickly eliminating candidates, the app needed to be highly customizable. I even considered trying to program my own. But then I tried [Fabulous][http://www.thefabulous.co/], and I almost dismissed it out of hand for not immediately allowing my to set a task. But then it asked me something I hadn’t thought about. “What you want?”… it honestly stopped me in my tracks, I scrolled through the four options and saw “Focus and Concentrate more”. That I thought, would be helpful, if not for my housekeeping then certainly for my studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then the app had me read a letter. It explained the importance of keeping a to-do list, and not in an app, but in a notebook, written out. It said, write the list everyday, and that will start you on your way. It has been two weeks and I have written in it everyday, and with each milestone they have sent me another letter explaining another good habit and, crucially for me, they explain how it is going to help and why it’s important. And now as I said I am getting more done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t always finish the list, but when something goes undone I know and can adjust appropriately. Now I am keeping the house better than my wife used to, writing more code, and writing more in general, I am also exercising more, and staying more on top of my job search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not say that it is due entirely to the app, I have been doing a lot of soul searching lately, and that has helped. I have also, in that search, found a lot of great resources, which I am sure I will talk about in the future. But the change did start with that question. “What do you want?” To be healthier, to be more productive, to have more energy, to be a better friend, to be a better parent? Start by answering the question and then write it down. Define the problem so you can understand it, start a to do list and put items on it that move you toward that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds too easy, but it’s not. It’s hard, there is no rule that says you have to be better. Most employers will tolerate sub-par performance, because everyone does it. No one will make you become the person you want to be, because that all want you to be someone else. But making change is not about large life altering events. It’s about small incremental steps. Write down those steps and start crossing them off. You can do it, I know because I am doing it. I am not special, or experienced, or especially motivated by nature. I just answered a question, and started a list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what do you want?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 08:43:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/productivity/2016/07/03/Getting-More-out-of-My-Life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/productivity/2016/07/03/Getting-More-out-of-My-Life/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Being a Better Listener</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I was listening to the latest episode of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tested.com/still-untitled-the-adam-savage-project/&quot;&gt;Still Untitled&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/donttrythis&quot;&gt;Adam Savage&lt;/a&gt; was talking about the smartest people he knows, and what he said was that they all frequently say the words “I don’t know”…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that was interesting because it reminded me that I don’t tend to ask many questions when talking with others. And in fact, I actually tend to answer questions that were not asked. I spend most of a conversation looking for some connection to something I have recently learned so that I can share it with everyone else. I have typically thought of this as normal, but it is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think this is why most people think that I am a know it all. In truth I don’t think i know everything and in most cases I am ready to learn so that I can be a more informed individual. It occurred to me that at the heart of being an active listener, is asking questions, engaging with the others, and find out more about what they care about and what they want. If what you want to do is monologue about what you’ve learned, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/m/signin?redirect=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F&quot;&gt;Start a blog!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But conversing with your friends and family should be about learning about your friends and family, and building and maintaining those bonds. And if you find that you are the only one asking questions, maybe talk about with them and let them know how you feel. I think everyone could do with being more empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I for one am challenging myself to ask at least one genuine question when every I speak with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have seen this lack of listening in yourself or others. What do you do when you notice it? Has anyone ever pointed it out to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they have, I recommend taking the same challenge, and start asking more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 09:23:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/relationships/2016/07/02/being-a-better-listener/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/relationships/2016/07/02/being-a-better-listener/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>relationships</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I&#39;ve Already Learned</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I outlined my current situation, but I skimmed over my actual software studies. I’m going to take one more post and lay out what I have learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school I took a summer course that taught me what HTML was and the basics of how to use it and then of the next few years I taught myself CSS and Javascript, well sort of. The farthest I got was js alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then until 6 months ago I basically abandoned coding and web design for other pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January of this year I have quainted myself with HTML, and filled in HTML5, and did the same with CSS and CSS3. I taught myself the basics of C++, and C#, which I am getting ready to take a class on. I have also found basically every JavaScript Tutorial I can get my hands on, and have learned a lot about jQuery, and DOM scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took a course in SQL which was fascinating, if a bit easy. And next up on my list of languages is PHP, so that I can get my JavaScript talking to MySQL. (I actually bought a Raspberry Pi and set it up as an apache server, running MySQL). So far, most of my interest lays in the web and front end development, but I suspect that is mostly because that is my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also been learning a lot about GitHub and the ins and outs of open source. Which I hope to turn into a major source of my extracurricular studies. Right now, my biggest source of practice and information is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;. I am about ⅓ the way through their material and loving courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also started working on Ruby, which feels so good to work with, and can’t wait to put something real together with it. So far, it has only been tutorials and small challenges. This, by the way, is how I have mostly been learning these various technologies and languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, however, put together several small projects from the Free Code Camp course map, which many reading this will likely be familiar with. I have completed and refactored, the WikiPedia search API, the Quote generator, the weather display. I have also worked on a small list maker app, right now it can’t store the list, but I am hoping to add this function soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these projects can be found on my portfolio site, which is currently displayed in markdown format on GitHub, but I am currently refactoring the portfolio to be a stand alone &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;jekyll site&lt;/a&gt;. As far as I can tell Jekyll is perfect for these kind of static sites that primarily act as an archive of writing and images. I have just started this process so I hope to document the process here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, like I said this should be the last list of things I am doing. For future post I hope to make these more casual and dealing directly with what I am learning.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 09:23:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/tech/learning/2016/07/01/what-ive-already-learned/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tech/learning/2016/07/01/what-ive-already-learned/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Over</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I  am answering the challenge that was put forward by &lt;a href=&quot;http://travisneilson.com/&quot;&gt;Travis Neilson&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travandlos.com/&quot;&gt;Late Nights with Trav and Los&lt;/a&gt; podcast, to write 200 words in the next three days. I have been meaning to start a blog for some time now, to document my education in software engineering, so I am seizing this moment to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last seven months I have been engaged in a quest to learn everything I can about software engineering, web development and computer science. I started by enrolling at a local tech Institute called New England Tech, and have been working through every tutorial and project I can find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also, through an unrelated set of events I also lost my job, so I have also been trying to find work, preferably in the same field. And to top everything off just Seven and a half months ago my wife and I had our first child…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken all together, it makes this year a year of starting over, and I have I think done my best to embrace the opportunity that such a crucible can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, seeing as this the first in a long series of posts documenting my progress. Let me take this first to record where I am currently for contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 30 years old, married, with a new baby. I graduated from high school in 2004 – where I discovered a love for web design and ceramics, and from Rhode Island College in 2009. I studied Fine Arts Sculpture with a focus on ceramics. I never followed up with Web design in college, mostly because I didn’t know enough to realize that web design is just a facet of graphic design which I could have majored in. But you live and learn. And after graduating that is exactly what I did. I taught myself photoshop, illustrator, inDesign, I learned the Silk-screen printing process and started entering in contests. In 2014, I landed an entry level design position at an up and coming tech company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me take a moment to express how amazing this position and company were. They were young and enthusiastic and passionate about both the company and the work we were doing. These things may not seem particularly unique, especially in the tech industry, but it was the first time I had ever experienced such a working environment. It was also, as it turned out, a turning point. After nine months of working there, the company decided that Rhode Island was not the best place for their headquarters and laid off just about everyone working in the Providence office. Including me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a pregnant wife and bills to pay, it was scramble time I spent the last 2 months there, looking for anywhere else that might take me. I wound up at a small novelty design company. Which was the polar opposite of the last job. The product was useless, and often uninspiring, the people were overworked and turnover was high. It became clear after the first few months that, while I had learned a ton about design and manufacturing, that I needed to get out of there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made a decision. I would go back to school, this time for software engineering, and I would get into a career where I might be head hunted, and where my skills would be valued. After enrolling, I sent my resume out to everyone I could find, and in April of this year found a position at Hasbro Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This had seriously been a fantasy of mine for years, but now it was time to prove myself, get my foot in the door and make something of myself… three days later they terminated my contract without so much as a good-bye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am unemployed, but working hard to develope my new skill set, while trying to change the way I run my life and keep my daughter safe and cared for. It is a crazy and stressful time, but I am hopeful that I will come through it stronger and faster than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 09:23:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/growth/career/2016/06/30/starting-over/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growth/career/2016/06/30/starting-over/</guid>
        
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 07:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll/update/2016/06/29/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll/update/2016/06/29/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
